Hello and welcome back. Now we are going to be talking about
欢迎回来 在这个视频里 我们将学习
curve evolution. This is the concept that is going to
曲线演化 这个概念将
bring us to the understanding of active contours as we have seen in the previous
有助于对前面几周所提到的主动轮廓的理解
week. And as we have talked in the previous
正如我们前几个视频中提到的那样
videos as well. So what is curve evolution?
什么是曲线演化
Very, very simple concept. The basic idea is that as we see here we
这个概念非常简单 基本思想就是像我们这里看到的一样
have a curve. And that every point we have a velocity
有一条曲线 曲线上每个点都对应一个速度向量
that defines how that curve is moving, and that's represented by this equation.
来表明曲线是如何运动的 可以用这个方程来表示
So it's a partial differential equation. If I'm going to write it in explicit
这是一个偏微分方程 如果用更详细的形式表达的话
form, it's going to say the derivative of the curve, remember the curve is
称之为这条曲线的导数 要记住
parameterized by a parameter p. The derivative of the curve in time.
这条曲线的参数是p 对时间t求导
So the curve is changing in time, is equal to certain velocity.
因此曲线随时间变化 这个式子等于固定的速度向量
And the velocity is again, at the given point.
速度向量的参数是给定的点p
And the velocity might be changing in time.
并随着时间t变化
So this is the complete equation. It's a partial differential equation and
这才是完整的方程 这是个偏导数方程
we write in shorter form as here we know that, that the subscripts represent
我们把它简写成这种形式 用下角标来表示导数
derivatives. So at every point we're moving the curve.
所以在每一点上曲线都在改变
So at some time we're going to have this curve.
有些时候我们的曲线是这样的
A bit later we might have a curve. Like here, and then a bit later we might
或者是像这样一条蓝色曲线 亦或是
have maybe a curve like this, depending on the velocity at every single point.
像这样的一条绿色曲线 这取决于每一个点的速度向量
And as we're going to see, this type of deformations of curves, remember, curves
我们来看这种类型的曲线变形 要记住
are boundaries of shapes. This type of deformations will bring us
曲线是形状的分界线 这种变形为我们带来
some very, very interesting. Movements inside images and inside
一些在图像或视频中极其有趣的变化
videos. So let us see a few properties of this
那让我们来看一下它的特征
and also a few examples that will illustrate the importance of this
我将会用几个例子来描述这一概念的重要性
concept. The first important property is the
第一个重要特征是跟踪
following. We have a velocity at every point that's
我们有每个点的速度向量
a deformation velocity. Now that velocity can be decomposed of
即变形速度向量 速度向量在运动方向上的向量
course, into the component that is normal to the curve, perpendicular to the curve.
分解后沿曲线的法线方向 或者说是垂直方向
We have defined normal as N tangents so we a vector we decompose it into it's
我们已经定义了法线和切线 因此可以把向量分解成
normal and tangent components. It turns out that this tension component
法线和切线方向的分量 结果表明这个方向上（切线方向）的分量
does not change the shape of the curve, so it's not relevant.
并不会改变曲线形状 所以这个分量和形变无关
So that's written here. This is the general equation that we
因此这里所写的式子 是一般方程
have, but we basically project the velocity towards the normal direction.
但我们把速度向量投影到法线方向
And with a, only that projection and we move in the normal direction.
投影仅沿着法线方向运动
So basically from the geometric point of view, the most general deformation is a
从几何观点来说 最常见的变形就是
deformation in the normal direction to the curve.
沿曲线的法线方向的变形
You can add velocities in the tangential direction.
你可以在切线方向增加速率
They just don't change the shape. Remember the tangent is the velocity you
但却改变不了曲线的形状 要记住 正切影响的是
are travelling the curve. So adding these terms, it's kind of
曲线变化的速率 有了这些概念 我们可以知道
changing the velocity the things are moving but they're moving along the
这也是一种速度的变化 但它仅仅沿着曲线移动
curve. They are not really deforming the shape.
它们不见得会引起曲线形状变化
Of the curves. So often we are going to just write curve
因此我们通常把曲线演化
evolution as deformations in the normal direction.
表示成法线方向上的变化
That's all what we care. Sometimes, for convenience, if you want,
这才是我们所关注 有时为了方便理解 如果喜欢
you can add tangential components. You can add them as you wish to add them,
也可以加入切线分量 随你所愿
because they don't deform the curve. For example, if I have a motion like
因为它们并不会改变曲线形状 例如 如果曲线是这样运动的
this, CT. Equal some function in the tangent
Ct等于某些包含正切方向分量的函数
direction. So, no normal component.
而不含法线分量
These, does not change the shape of the curve at all.
这样一点也不会改变曲线的形状
Its only like, making a lot of effort, around the curve, but not changing the
就好像是一直在绕着曲线跑 但最终对曲线形状
curve at all. So the general, the formations are in the
并没造成什么影响 因此形状还是由法线方向决定
normal direction. Lets just talk about more about that, and
让我们来进一步探讨
lets just see a few examples. By the way, these properties, not very
先看几个例子 顺便说一下 这些性质
hard to prove, and you can do that as an exercise, if you wish to do so.
并不难证明 大家愿意的话可以自己做个练习
So, the first one that we want to talk is what's called curvature motion.
我们首先探讨的是“曲率运动”
So, the deformation. In the normal direction is proportional
法线方向上的形变是与
to the curvature at that point. Before I tell you what basically that
这个点的曲率成比例的 在我们了解
type of deformation is doing to the curve, let's just look a bit more.
这种类型的变形前 先做一些铺垫
Remember that the second derivative of the curve.
对于曲线的二阶导数
When we take the derivative with respect to the Euclidian arc length is this.
我们对它的欧氏弧长求导 就是这个
So the second derivative of the curve, we know, is a vector perpendicular to the
曲线的二阶导数 就是和曲线垂直的向量
curve. And the magnitude of that vector is the
这些向量的大小就是曲率
curvature. So this deformation, is like the first
因此对这个变形而言 就好像一阶导数
derivative in time equal second derivative according to arc length.
恰好等于弧长的二阶导数
For those that are familiar a bit more with differential equations, this is
这要求对微分方程有所了解
like. What's called the heat flow based very
这被称为“热流”
geometric because of this arc length. So in explicit form, this says that dC.
由于弧长 基于较强的几何特性 因此确切形式应该是
Dt is equal to the second derivative of C.
dC比上dt 等于 C对弧长所求的二阶导数
According to the arc length. Okay?
明白了吗？
it's a very interesting. Deformation of curves.
很有趣吧 曲线的变形
And what it does, it basically first of all, is Euclidean invariant.
首先是欧氏空间的不变量
Curvature is Euclidean invariant, meaning it's invariant to rotations and
曲率就是欧氏空间不变量 就是说旋转和移动
translations and the normal is also Euclidean invariant.
都不会改变的量 法线同样也是欧氏空间不变量
So if you do a rotation and translation or an Euclidean transform and.
因此如果旋转平移 或者欧氏变换
First you do the deformation and you do the deformation here.
如果是进行这样一个变化 和这样一种变化
Also here. Along the way of the deformation, the
以及这种 依照这样的变换方式
curves are related by exactly the same rotation and translation.
曲线会进行完全一样的旋转和平移
So you start from two, from a curve, you rotate it.
因此当开始旋转一组曲线时
You start the form in both, according to this motion.
通过这种运动方式同时进行
And any time you stop, the same rotation and translation relates the deformed
无论任何时候停下来 曲线旋转和平移的变化都是一致的
curve. That will happen as long as you use.
百试不爽
Properties which are invariant to rotation and translation.
旋转和平移是无法改变这些属性的
Now this motion does some very beautiful things to curves.
这种运动方式能对曲线进行意想不到的操作
And the basic idea. And this has been proven, a number of
这一点已经被无数次地证明了
times. But was first proved by Grayson some time
最早是由Grayson二十多年前证明的
ago. Then you take any curve.
无论对于什么样的曲线
Think about any curve that is not self intersecting.
只要不是自相交的
So that's called a simple curve. That's actually the boundary of a shape.
就是所谓的简单曲线 形状是有边界的
You take any cure, you deform with these. And the curve becomes convex.
对于一个曲线来说 如果按照这个公式变化 这个曲线就会变为凸曲线
It just opens up. It just gets very smoothly into a convex
它就像被打开了一样 变成一种非常平滑的凸形曲线
shape. Once it convex, if you keep going, starts
当成形成凸曲线以后 如果继续这样变化的话
rounding. And basically, it ends in what's called a
就会变成一个圆形 最终会变成一个圆点
round point. So it actually will vanish, it will keep
它会不断缩小 直到慢慢消失
shrinking. Basically we keep going inside
换句话说
proportional to the curvature. And at the end, it would look like a
收缩是与曲率成正比的 到最后看上去就和一个圆点一样
round point. So if you dilate it all the time.
因此如果一直向外扩张它
If you just make the area constant all the time, you will see this becoming
一直保持其区域范围 将会看到它变得越来越圆
round and round. So what you see is that no matter how
因此无论看到的曲线形状
crazy and how difficult your shape is. As long as it doesn't self-intersect.
是多么的夸张和复杂 只要它不是自相交的
And basically, it just opens up, so it's becoming smoother and smoother, until it
那么它就会展开 然后变得越来越光滑
becomes a circle. Remember, the circle has constant
直到它变成一个圆 记住 圆的曲率是常数
curvature. So this is basically going from a very
而这却源自一个奇形怪状的曲线
crazy curve. It might be a curve that does a lot like
比方说这个乱七八糟的曲线
this. As much as you want, and then smoothly.
只要一直这么做 就会让它越来越光滑
Is becoming, just nicer, so it's actualizing regularizing the curve.
变得看上去顺眼些 这实际上是规则化曲线
And if you wait all the way, it becomes round.
如果能不厌其烦一直处理下去 就会变成一个圆
Constant curvature. If you remember, the heat flow takes
一个有着固定曲率的圆 大家应该知道 热流携带热量
heat, no matter the distribution of the heat, at the end becomes constant in the
无论热量分布如何 最终会在房间里形成稳定状态
room. This, no matter what the curvature is all
放在这里来说 就是无论曲线的曲率如何
around, at the end it becomes constant. It becomes one over the radius.
最终都会变为常量 即半径的倒数
How much it takes it to get to here? We're going to know that in a couple of
想变成这样需要进行多少步？我们一会儿就会知道
minutes. Don't worry, this is a very simple
别担心 要证明曲线完全
property to prove how long it takes for the curve to completely collapse into
塌陷成这个圆点所需要的步数 是很容易的
this round point. Before we do that, let's do a couple of
在证明之前 让我们举几个另外的例子
additional examples. Now that was the Euclidean case.
在欧氏几何的前提下
What about the fine case? The fine case turns out to be this
什么是仿射状态？仿射状态就是得到这个函数
function. This is the Euclidean curvature.
这就是欧氏曲率
Where do we get it from? We are going to do, let me just write it
如何得到的这个方程？让我在这里写一下
here for a second. We are going to do the same as we did
我们先像以前一样写出这个式子
before. But now.
不同的是
According to the affine arc length. Now remember when you take second
现在要对仿射弧长求二阶导数
derivative according to the affine arc length, you are not necessarily
并不需要和曲线保持垂直
perpendicular to your curve. But, we know that the tangential
但我们也知道正切分量无关紧要
component does not matter. So you have to project it.
因此必须求这个的投影
And we already saw before, in one of the previous videos, that the projection of
在之前的视频中我们已经了解过
the fine normal, the second derivative, into the Euclidean normal, is kappa to
仿射法线 也就是二阶导数得到的欧氏法线等于
the one third. Is the curvature to the one third.
Κ的1/3次幂 即曲率的1/3次幂
So. These two equations, are from the
所以 这两个方程从几何角度来说
geometric point of view, equivalent. They are absolutely the same equation.
是等价的 它俩是绝对相等的
But these has motion in the tangent direction, that is not relevant, so once
然而这个方程的正切方向对曲线没有影响 因此
we project it, to the normal direction, we get this beautiful equation.
把它投影到法线方向 我们就得到了这个漂亮的方程
Looks like a Uclidian, that has a magic exponent, that makes it a fine invariant,
看上去像是欧氏空间里有一个神奇的指数 使其保持仿射不变
that means. That if I take a shape and I do an affine
换言之 如果我有一个形状 想把它通过仿射变换
transform of that shape and now I evolve. Both of them, then all the time I can
变成这个形状 所以就对它们俩进行了变换
relate them by exactly the same a fine transform.
于是它们就一直进行着相同的仿射变换
So this is a fine invariant. So I can be doing smoothing in a fine
这就是一种仿射不变 因此我们可以通过这种规则化的方式
regularization cleaning my curve in a fine variant fashion meaning invariant to
在仿射变换中来平整曲线 即保持镜头倾斜度不变
tilts of the camera. When we are under the assumptions that
正如我们之前讨论的一样
the fine model is a good model, as we discussed before.
我们假设仿射模型是一个好模型
And now, you can also prove a number of interesting properties.
现在你可以证明一些有趣的特性
Similarly to the Euclidian case, what happens here is that the curve, no matter
与欧氏条件下相似 无论这个曲线是什么样的
how crazy it is, it becomes. Convex again and then it goes into an
它都会变成凸曲线 然后变成
ellipse. It doesn't go into a circle.
一个椭圆 但不是一个圆
We are in a fine domain. Circles and ellipses are the same in the
在仿射域中 圆和椭圆
fine domain because a, a circle within a fine transform goes into an ellipse.
会变成一样的 因为圆经过仿射变换就变成了椭圆
Moreover, the lips has constant. Affine curvature.
同时 边缘也是恒定的仿射曲率
Remember this mu that we discussed. That is the affine curvature.
这里的所讨论的μ就是指仿射曲率
So as in the Euclidean case, we start from something that might have a crazy
如欧氏条件下一样我们可能从稀奇古怪的仿射曲率开始
affine curvature. Slowly, the, this crazy or this very
然后慢慢地让这个怪异的仿射曲率变化
change in the affine curvature is deforming towards constant affine
直到形成恒定的仿射曲率
curvature. And that's why this is called the affine
这就是为什么这一部分叫做仿射热流
heat flow. It's taking curvature that is very non
把曲率从差异很大
uniform and it's making it uniform at the end.
最终统一起来
So that's another very interesting motion.
还有另一个非常有趣的运动
They're clearly an undefined. They're both kind of cleaning the curves,
还没有被明确定义 也是平整曲线或是平整形状
meaning, cleaning the shapes. Now, not every motion does that.
的一种方法 然而不是每种运动都是这样的
If we take the simplest of the motions, constant speed in the normal direction,
拿最简单运动来说 在法线方向上每一个点 移动每一步
just at every point, move a step. I don't care the curvature, about the
都保持匀速 也不关心曲线的曲率
curvature of my curve. I just move a step at every single point.
仅是一步一步一个点一个点地移动
Now. This is a very important equation.
这是一个非常重要的方程
It's the question that creates offsets. You're creating a curve which is parallel
是创建等距曲线的等式 意味着你创建一条
to the previous curve. You can move inwards or you can do minus
和之前曲线平行的曲线 你既可以在里面移动 也可以在这里填个减号
here and move outwards. So you're creating another curve that is
使其在外面移动 这样你就可以创建另一条平行曲线了
parallel. It is equal distance all the time.
时时刻刻都是等距的
And basically if you keep going you get another equal distance and then you get
如果你要继续取另一条等距曲线
another equal distance here and so on depending how far you go.
再往里取另一条等距曲线一直到你不再取为止
Remember this is a differential equation in time.
这同时也是一个微分方程
You can stop or you can keep going. Now this curve is obtained by doing this
你可以决定停止还是继续计算 这个曲线是通过
deformation, but is also obtained in the following fashion.
这个变形方程得到的 但也可以通过下面的方法获得
You, draw a circle centered on the curve and with a given radius.
你可以以曲线上的点为圆心按照给定半径做圆
And then for every point you draw a circle with exactly the same radius.
圆上的每个点都是以相同半径做出的
And then you take the envelope. Of that circle and that gives you this.
然后可以通过这些圆所构成包络线  得到
Constant motion deformation. And that's related to what's called
恒定的运动变化 类似现象在物理学上称作
Huygens principle in physics. That's how waves propagate, basically
惠更斯原理 指波在没有障碍物的情况下
when they don't have obstructions. So, if you had, maybe you did this
是如何传播的 如果你做过这个物理实验的话
experiment in physics, where you where you basically propagate waves and that's
这种恒定运动就如同
what this constant motion does for the Huygens principal.
惠更斯原理中光的传播一样
So maybe you knew that the... So this is a wave.
因此你可以把这个曲线比作波
And maybe you knew the Huggins principle basically is the one that governs the
你也许知道在惠更斯原理中波在没有障碍物的情况下
motion of the waves without any obstructions.
的运动原理
So that's just nothing else than this type of curve evolution.
这种曲线演化就讲到这里
So, this kind of revolution is important in image processing, but it also explains
这种演化在图像处理中很重要 而且它还能够解释
a lot of very interesting physical phenomena.
很多非常有趣的物理现象
Constant motion. Now this constant motion is very
恒定运动 这种恒定运动很有趣
interesting. For example, it can actually change the
比方说，它可以改变曲线的
topology of a curve. If you start from this curve.
拓扑结构 如果你从外面这条曲线出发
And then you move with constant velocity, after awhile the curve splits in two.
匀速向内运动的话 一会这个曲线就会分成两半
This cannot happen in the curvature motion for Euclidean or affine that we
这是在欧氏或者仿射的曲率运动不可能出现的
saw. The curve stays simple, stays smooth.
曲率运动中曲线保持简单和光滑
Here actually it can split into pieces, it's like the waves can split into
而这里却把它分成两部分 就像波也能够分成两部分一样
pieces. There are even more things happening, if
还有更多可能发生的事情
you start with a smooth curve and you move inwards after awhile these sides
如果你从一条光滑的曲线向内运动 过一会两边就会
will collapse. They don't have a curvature term here so
折叠起来 这里不存在曲率的概念
they don't have any way to understand that the curvature is becoming very, very
难以理解的是曲率会变得非常非常高
high. It's going to collapse.
从而趋向于折叠
It's going to get to a corner. Corner has infinite curvature.
趋向于形成夹角 角的曲率可是无穷大的
Just you, really turn very fast. That's a no, because there is no
变化得非常快 曲率的概念
curvature term here. So after some time it will basically
在这里是不存在的  几次计算过后
collapse and it will create what are called shocks.
就会折叠 称之为“冲激”
And we know that from waves. When waves are coming, they can collapse.
这个概念来自波 当波在传播过程中发生折叠
And they can create these shocks. This doesn't happen with curvature
就能够产生出这些冲激 这不会在理想状态和欧氏状态下
motions for the fine or Euclidean case. The curve stays smooth all the time.
的曲率运动中发生 曲率运动中曲线一直保持光滑
It will never collapse. The constant flow creates this collapse.
永远也不会发生折叠 恒流产生了这种折叠
So we have the both extremes. The constant flow can change topology.
通过这两个极端例子可以看出恒流能够改变拓扑结构
Can collapse things. Can create corners.
能够折叠物体 产生夹角
Now. The curvature regularizes discrete
好 曲率规则化、夹角分离化
corners so maybe it sharpens shapes, so we have both motions depending on what we
也许能够锐化形状 这两种运动方式的选用取决于
want to do in the image processing arena. Now once we have this type of.
我们想在图像处理中做什么 现在我们有了
Curvature motions. And I'm basically going to write them
曲率运动的方式 我又把它们写在这了
here again, so you remember them. We have the constant flow.
让你能记住这些公式 我们有了恒流
No speed here, or speed equal one. The curvature flow Euclidan, and the fine
没有写速度 这里速度是1 欧氏曲率流 仿射流
flow. The constant motion can split curves, can
恒定运动能够分开曲线
do. Can do shocks, can do corners.
能够形成冲激 能够形成夹角
That gradient one regularizes everything into a circle and affine regularizes
第二种梯度的规则化能够把所有曲线转化成圆 仿射的规则化
everything into an ellipse. Which ellipse?
能够把所有曲线变成椭圆 什么样的椭圆呢？
We don't know, we have fine space. All ellipses are the same.
我们也不知道 在仿射空间中所有的椭圆都一样
Now, we can write a lot of properties of these deformation, and those are just
现在 我们可以写变化的很多特性出来 这仅仅是
interesting curiosity, sometimes, they are very useful for image processing,
兴趣所致 有时它们在图像处理中非常管用
sometimes, they are just nice things, one of the things, we are going to see is,
有时它会让曲线变得好看 我们还要关注的一点是
when does these curve in the Uchlion case collapses, and this is just some
这些曲线在欧氏状态下可以折叠 仅仅进行一些
calculus, so its not very hard to do. But if you take a certain deformation, so
微积分运算 因此不算太难 如果你要用这种变形
remember we only consider the normal deformation, and with velocity with speed
只需考虑速度V的法线变形
V. So for example how is the length
举个例子，曲线长度L
changing, and deforming the curve. What's happening to the length of curve?
是如何改变的 它会发生怎样的变化？
So we have to take the derivative of the length.
因此我们要对长度L求导
And this is. The definition of the length of curve, so
曲线的长度是指
it's the interval all around the curve. That's the symbol with the circle there
环绕曲线一整周的区间 用符号∮来表示
as you go all around the curve, we're talking about closed curves, in this
绕曲线一周 这里我们所讨论的是闭合曲线
case. So you go all around the curve and this
因此要求绕曲线一周的长度
is the function of basically the length. Now I have to put the derivative inside
这里就是求长度的函数 现在我对尖括号里的项求导
and we have already seen that we take the derivative of the first component.
这里用第一项的导数乘以
* the second + the second * the first. These are symmetric.
第二项+第二项乘以第一项 左右对称
So that's why we get these two here and then we get here and we're going to have
这就是为什么我们要求得这两项 接下来看这里 我们要
to reverse the order here of derivatives. And instead of c derivative with respect
调换这里导数的顺序 先对CP求导数
to p and then t, we're going to reverse that.
然后对 求导数 就可以调换这两项了
So it's a bit of calculus and we get at the end these expressions.
经过一系列运算 最终能够得到这个表达式
So this is the expression that governs the change of length.
这个表达式决定了长度的变化
And we're going to see an example in a second for different v's.
我们可以下面的例子来看一下不同V
We can do the same for area. We basically, instead of inner product,
我们可以用同样的方法来计算区域面积 用外积
we take the outer product or the determinant.
或者行列式来替代内积
We have already seen that. We take basically the two vectors.
我们可以用两个向量
And we take the determinant of that matrix.
用矩阵的行列式
And that computes area. We can also look at the change of
来计算区域面积 我们也可以计算曲率的变化
basically curvature. And these are the questions.
这些都是适用的问题
Again, I don't want to take too much time to do the whole derivation.
我不想花费太多时间完整证明这些式子
They're not very hard. And.
它们都不太难 而且
They appear in the book, for example, that, that I mentioned, but here we have
我提到的书中都有相应的例子 这些式子是
the. General formulas of the change of length,
计算长度、区域面积、曲率的
area and curvature. This is actually a very interesting
一般公式 这个式子可是一个非常有趣
formula. It's basically, in some cases, it's
公式 在某些情况下
called a reaction diffusion equation. It's the same type of equations that
称之为“反应扩散方程” 这一方程
people use to model how, basically, patterns in the skin, patterns in the
被人们用来对皮肤、条纹的模式进行建模
zebra are created. It has kind of a diffusion term.
它是一种扩散的概念
And it has kind of a shock term here for certain types of V.
这里这个V也是冲激概念的一种
So let's just pick some examples and see what happens for different V's, for.
让我们来举几个例子 看看不同V的区别
Example for V equal one, the constant motion.
比如当V=1时 就会保持恒定运动
So for the constant motion we have V equal one, and then the change of length
对于恒定运动来讲V=1 长度L的变化
we put here, V equal one. So it's the integral all around the curve
我们令V=1 对整条曲线
from zero to L. Now.
从0到L积分
There is integral of the curvature around a closed curve, it's always equal to two
整条闭合曲线曲率的积分等于2π
Pi, that's basic fundamental theorem in differential geometry.
这是微分几何学中的基本定理
And that basically says that the length is changing at constant rate.
换句话说就是长度以恒定速率变化
The length is changing so the derivative of the length is changing at constant
长度变化保持不变 也就是说长度的导数是个常数
length. And that, if you.
如果你
Integrate that, it tells you. When, are you starting to see.
把这两个式子合并 将会告诉你何时
Crazy things happening, as we're going to see in a second.
你能够看到意想不到的事情发生
So, the time. That things change.
也就是变化发生的时间
So you can either. Write it as a function of the, initial
因此你可以选择写出带初始长度的方程
length or as a function of time. You get it here.
或者带时间的方程 都可以用这里的式子表示出来
The are is basically, this was the general formula, that V=1, and basically
面积区域的一般方程中 令V=1
we have the integral from zero to L of one, that's L.
从0到L积分 结果为L
So, the area is changing proportional to the length.
因此面积的变化是和长度成比例
Now, the length is changing. So, this is not constant.
而长度却是变化而不是常数
This is constant, this is not constant. The area is changing, proportional to the
上面式子是常数 而这个不是 面积的变化率和长度成比例
length. The curvature.
对于曲率来说
This was the general formula. And we have the, then the derivative is
这是它的一般方程 它的导数等于
equal to the curvature^2. Because V is constant.
它的平方 因为V是常数
So second derivative vanishes. Now you can solve this equation of
因此二阶导数就把V消去了 现在你可以利用变化的时间等于曲率的平方来解决
derivative of curvature according to time equal curvature^2.
曲率导数的等式了
You solve it, and you get this equation. And look what happens here.
最后求解的结果就是这个等式 看看会发生什么
This, basically, the curvature blocks. It becomes infinity.
这个式子中曲率变化受阻 变为无穷大
When t is one over the curvature at the original curve.
当t等于原曲线曲率的导数时
Remember, we say that things can create shocks.
就产生了所谓的冲激
Basically, the waves are coming, and boom, they collapse.
换言之 波向内聚集产生碰撞后发生了折叠
And that's basically very high curvature, infinite curvature.
产生了极高的接近无穷的曲率
When that happens, when this term is zero.
那会怎么样呢 当这一项为0的时候
When is that happening? When t is one over the initial curvature
当t等于这个点的无限大曲率的倒数时
at this point. One over curvature is radius.
曲率倒数也就是半径
So you know exactly when are you expecting a shock to happen.
因此你应该清楚什么时候冲激会产生
When are you expecting these waves from both sides to collapse?
什么时候这些波会从两边向中间折叠
You go around your initial, initial curve.
从最初的曲线开始
And you say, where do I have, basically, my curvature?
然后以这种形式得到曲率
Of this form. When is that going to happen?
什么时候会发生那样的情况？
When is this curvature going to become infinity, because it's collapsing from
当曲率趋于无穷大时 从两边
both sides. Oh, at time one over the curvature.
向内折叠 哦！时间就是曲率的倒数
The larger the curvature, the shorter the time it will become a shock.
曲率越大 这个过程所用的时间就越短
So if you have something which is already almost, almost a corner very fast, it
因此如果你发现你的取值使其非常快地接近一个角时
will become a shock. So from these equations, you understand
冲激就会产生 从这些方程中 你能够理解
the. Overall behavior of that.
整个过程
You can, of course, do that also for the curvature flow for the Euclidean case and
你当然可以在欧氏状态下求曲率流
once again you plug in the same equations and in this case.
再说一遍 你在这种情况下带入同一个方程
This is the general formula of the area. Now, the velocity now is curvature.
这是面积的一般方程 速度相当于曲率
So you integrate, again, the integral of the curvature is constant.
积分后 得到曲率的积分是个常数
So you get that in the constant motion, the length was changing at constant rate.
因此你知道这是恒定运动 长度是以恒定速率变化
In the Uclindian motion, the area in the Uclidian curvature motion, the area is
在欧氏曲率运动中的面积是以
changing at constant rate. And then, I can solve for these, and I
恒定的速率变化 我可以通过这样的方式
can tell youi exactly, when is the curve collapsing, It is collapsing at time,
明确的告诉你 当曲线在t时刻折叠时
which is the initial area, divided by two party.
面积会变为无穷大 最终分裂为两部分
So you look at your initial area, you divide by two pi and say, at this time my
因此面积区域无穷大时 然后除以2π
whole curve will become a point. Remember this motion.
这时整个曲线就变成了一个点 这种运动
Collapses everything to a point that all the way smooth in contrast with a
和恒定运动不同的是把一切折叠成一个点时
constant motion. Here everything is smooth.
一切都是光滑的
It just gets cleaner and cleaner and it goes into a round point.
变得越来越平整知道形成一个圆点
At when exactly at this time. So that's why these formulas are
这时候的时间也可以精确求出 这就是为什么这些公式
important to understand how the length is changing, how the area is changing, or
对于理解长度、面积、曲率如何变化
even hos the curvature is changing. So these are really, really interesting
有着重要意义 这都是些非常非常有趣的
properties. We can do the same for the fine case, and
特性 我们也可以在仿射状态下
you get this formulas, there is no kind of, very.
有了这些公式 却没有一种
Clean way to solve this type of integrals.
清晰的方法能够求解这种积分
So you just get these formulas. There's no constant basically things
也只是有这些公式 而不能得到常量
here, although you can make an interpretation of some of the things as
尽管常量能够说明一些事情
constants but let's just not discuss about that in this moment.
我们在这里还是不要讨论了
So basically we have properties of these motions.
现在我们掌握了这些运动的特性
Now. One of the motions, so these are
一种运动 诸如
curvature motions, constant motions. The active contours we talk about
曲率运动曲率运动、常量运动等 我们所要讨论的主动轮廓
basically are these type of deformations. Nothing else in that.
不外乎这些变形的一种
And then I'll just give you one example of active contour's velocity and when we
我举一个主动轮廓速度的例子 当我们
learn in one of the next videos, calculus of variations, after that we're going to
在学习下一节视频“变分法”以后 我们就能够
be able to derive this motion in a more formal way, but even now I can write it
用一种更好的方式导出这种运动状态  不过现在我就能写出来
down and explain it to you. So this is V.
然后解释这个公式 这一块就是V
What we have here is b. So this equation looks very long, but
我在这里标出来 这个式子看上去很长
it's nothing else than a deformation with a certain velocity in the normal
但无外乎法线方向特定的速度造成的变形
direction. Now what are the terms inside here?
里面这些项都是什么意思呢？
So this curve. Is basically going to deform with a
对于这个曲线 按照特定的速度
certain velocity. Now what are these terms?
来变形 都涉及到哪些项？
Here's the curvature. No problem.
这一项是曲率 没问题吧
We know it. Here's the normal.
这我们已经知道了 n是法线
What's g?
诺 这项就是法线 那么g是什么？
G is, for example, is a function that depends on the image, and, for example,
g是取决于图像的一个函数 例如
one over the gradient of the image. Now, why do we need this function?
图像梯度的倒数 为什么我们需要这个函数？
Let's say that this function was not here.
这里先不谈这个函数
Let's just leave aside this term for a second.
把这一项先放一边
Let's assume that this function was never here, so we have city equal K, kappa,
我们假设这个函数不存在 就得到Ct等于K 即曲率
curvature, collapses to a point. I don't want that.
收缩到一个点  我不打算这样
I want this red curve here. Basically, to stop, basically, add the
我想让这条红色的曲线 最终能够
boundaries of the shapes. I don't want it to collapse to a point.
收缩到这些物体形状的边界上 我可不想让它收缩成一个点
So how do I do that? I make it stop at high gradients.
那么怎么办呢？ 我让它在较高梯度时就停止收缩
So if g is proportional to one over the gradient of the image.
就另g与图像梯度的导数成比例
Then, let's say that I have a very strong boundary.
那么 我想要一个非常清晰的分界线
The gradient is very high. Let's assume it's infinity.
梯度就要求很高 我们假设梯度无穷大
And then G is zero. So the curvature's trying to collapse,
g就等于0 因此曲率就一直收缩收缩
collapse, but it gets multiplied by zero and then stops, say, hey, I cannot move
直到乘以0停止 然后它说 啊！我不能再动啦
any more. I need to stop.
我必须停下来
There is no more velocity. And that's why you have this term here.
我没有速度了 这就是为什么要有这一项
Now. We never have ideal shapes.
从来不会有理想的形状
So this derivative of G. Remember, G is one over derivative of the
因此这个g的导数 要记住g是图像导数的倒数
image. For example, the gradient, or any other
例如 梯度或者其他类型的函数
type of function. You take another derivative of that to
你用另一种方式求导
make that stopping term even stronger, even when there are no perfect edges.
使其速度停止项更强大 甚至没有完美的边界
That this will not be zero. You basically create that potential
这也不会为0 你相当于通过二阶导数
valley by taking the second derivative, and of course that doesn't have to be in
得出了一个势能谷 当然不必非得沿法线方向
the normal direction, so you have to project without that.
因此你必须投影到法线方向
Every time we have something that's not in the normal direction, we have to
每当式子中不含法线方向时 我们必须
project it to the normal direction. So this is almost nothing else than
投影到法线方向 这是曲率运动中
curvature motion. So, a simplified version of active
尤其值得注意的 这是对主动轮廓的
counters is this. Its curvature motion.
简要描述 这是曲率运动
In the normal direction multiplied by G. G is a function of your image, it's the
在法线方向上乘以g g是你图像的一个函数
one that tells stop when you get to very high gradients and this second term just
当梯度非常高的时候就提示停止 第二项仅仅
made that stopping even stronger. So here it is, we saw active counters in
使停止过程更强大 前几周我们所看到过主动轮廓
the previous week and now we have been talking about differential geometry and
现在我们在微分几何学的基础上探讨
we have been talking about. Curvature, curve motions and how things
在曲率、曲线运动以及物体变形的基础上探讨
deform, why, one of the reasons is to get to active counters, you're an expert now
为什么这样做呢？ 一个原因就是要获得主动轮廓 在微分几何学上这
in differential geometry, you're an expert now in.
你已经是个专家了 在曲线演化、曲线构成上
Curve evolution, curve the formation. So here it is.
你也是个专家了 就这么简单
You could have to sign this. If I give you five minutes to say, define
你必须记下来 如果我给你五分钟时间让你
this sign of curve evolution motion that will get you active contours.
给曲线演化运动获取主动轮廓下个定义
Many of you, most of you probably would have come with this solution.
你们中大多数人可能会用这种方式定义
Just deform it smoothly, move towards the objects.
让形状更光滑 不断向物体移动
But when you get to the objects, stop. And then people have done many different
一旦接触到物体就停止 人们已经衍生出
variations of these. But this is the underlying concept.
各种各样的解决方案 但这个概念仍是最基础的
You can add some constant motion. That helps you to move faster, but be
你可以加入一些恒定运动 能够帮助你移动得更快
very careful you can get shocks and you can you keep moving.
要注意的是 你可以得到冲激 也可以继续移动
So always you have to have turns that depend on the image, not just depend on
这都取决于图像 而不仅仅取决于
the curve, depend on the image. So it makes you stop.
曲线的形状 图像这才是停止的条件
And you can basically go wide and do very, very interesting things in Curve
你可以进一步用曲线演化中做些非常有趣的尝试
evolution to get to active contours. Now remember, we know how to define these
来获得主动轮廓 现在我们知道如何
properties also for surfaces. So we could do that for surfaces as well
定义这些特性 对曲面也一样 因此我们能够在曲面上这样做
and basically, here is just an example of a surface.
这里有一个曲面演化的例子
So these are snapshots of a surface that started basically from here.
这是曲面从这里开始演化的照片
And it deform, it deform, it deform and it is covered inside.
它不断变形不断变形 最终套在了一起
They were basically two rings basically touching each other.
像两枚戒指一样 相互重叠
And this motion is nothing else than the motion I just wrote for you but now in
这种运动是我写出来的唯一的一种运动
surface domain and here, this was an ideal object, white and black, so the
但在曲面区域这里 都是理想的物体 黑白分明
gradient was very strong and one of the, over the gradient was very weak.
因此梯度非常明显 梯度的倒数会非常小
So basically when I did the surface evolution, dS, dt equal let's say, one of
当我进行曲面演化时 dS/dt等于
the curvatures and, can be the Gaussian, can be the mean.
曲率的一种 可以是高斯分布 也可以取均值
Yeah we could discuss more about that, what curvature exactly to put here.
这里究竟该是什么样的曲率
The normal direction, that would basically move, move, move and then we
法线方向 不断移动移动移动 然后
have G, that basically you say, we'll say, when you get to a very, very high
这里有个g 会告诉你当梯度很高的时候
gradients, stop. And so this is just a ve, artificial
该停止了 这仅仅是人造的例子
example. We're going to see more examples of
在成为曲线演化专家的路上
active contours later on now that we're becoming experts in this curve evolution
我们将会看到更多主动轮廓的例子
and differential geometry and this is just, as I say, snapshots of this
要我说微分几何学就是这种演化的快照
evolution. So a lot of very interesting mathematical
有很多有趣的数学工具
tools. That give us, active counters, which is
帮助我们找到主动轮廓
one of the most useful techniques for doing image segmentation, as we have seen
它们是图像分割技术中最有效的技术之一
many examples last week and as we're going to keep looking at more examples.
上周我们已经看到很多例子 我们还将会看到更多的应用
So now we're experts on curve evolution. And I'm looking forward to seeing you in
现在我们都是曲线演化方面的专家了 很期待在之后的视频中看到你
the next video when we're going to keep learning, keep building the tools that
届时我们将共同学习 构建帮助我们
will let us understand everything about these active counters and this type of
理解关于主动轮廓、变形类型以及之后材料
deformation as well as some of the material coming later on.
一切的工具
Thank you very much and see you in the next video.
非常感谢大家 我们下个视频见